SUSAN POWELL

2847 Cypress Drive, Dallas, TX 75023 eiriail@youremail.com {214} 284-2847

Human resources executive with over 15 years of experience in hiring and retention, conflict resolution, labor-management and benefits administration, Proven experience collaborating with senior management to achieve the strategic goals of the company. Demonstrated results working with department heads to reduce employee turnover and improve employee job satisfaction. Demonstrated experience with cost-containment strategies that reduce payroll expenses. Specific knowledge in creating comprehensive benefits packages for employees.

EDUCATION

BACHELORS OF SCIENCE IN HUMAN RESOURCES

The University of Texas, Austin September 2000-May 2004

KEY SKILLS

- · Build good working relationships
- Organized
- Strong sense of urgency
- Working knowledge of employment laws and regulations
- Excellent written and verbal communication skills
- Flexible
- · High attention lo detail

CERTIFICATIONS

* Professional in Human Resources

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HUMAN RESOURCES DIRECTOR

Texas Instruments Corporation, Dallas, TX June 2016-Press nt

HUMAN RESOURCES MANAGER

DoubleTree Hotel, Richardson, TX March 2012June 2016

HUMAN RESOURCES MANAGER Hilton Garden Inn, Allen, TX

March 2008-February 2012

HUMAN RESOURCES ASSISTANT Kramer Industries, Austin, TX June 2004-January 2008

- Encourage department heads to improve the overall performance of staff, people movement and engagement 10 improve each managers capabilities
- Develop new hire training strategies and created content for specific development programs
- · Implement and administer company benefits packages
- Responsible for strategic workforce planning and talent development initiatives
- Deliver targeted solutions to build a high-performing organization and maintained a "great place to work" environment
- Worked with Hilton's Department of Learning and Development to facilitate regular talent development plans
- · Collaborated on ongoing HR projects to ensure employees maintain company standards
- Created manpower plans and strategized recruitment to meet the changing demands of the hotel
- Coached department heads to complete each employee's performance management plans and reviews
- Developed compensation and benefits program
- Completed different staffing needs, including conflict resolution, mediating disputes, hiring and recruitment and terminating employees
- Maintained the recruitment life cycle process, including interviewing, attending hiring fairs, negotiating compensation packages and onboarding new employees
- Oversaw all day-to-day HR responsibilities, including salary and bonus planning, staffing, performance management and reporting/analytics
- Create job descriptions and new hire training plans
- Drive organization design, workforce planning and sourcing and staffing
- Reconciled payroll and taxes
- Assisted with developing company benefits packages under the direction of the HR Director
- Conducted ongoing employee training to ensure company goals are supported
- Head of company Safety Committee and planned monthly safety meetings and training classes